I've been trading for over eight years and I've been trading for over seven. Together,
after 15 years of trading experience using the same simple system that helped us become profitable,
in this video we'll break down the simplest way to become a day trader in 2026 and the exact
steps we'd take if we had to start from zero. We'll cover the tools you need to start trading,
broker setup, technical analysis, a simple strategy we trade every day to have results like this,
this and this to even a special bonus on how to execute like a professional trader. The best part
is no matter if you're a beginner with a few hundred dollars or an expert, by the end of the video,
you'll learn the exact steps and systems on exactly what we've learned in the past 15 years
in a simplified way. So if you're ready to learn, hit the like button down below and let's get right
into the video. So in this video, we're going to go over the full trading course of everything we
wish we had when we started trading in the beginning of our careers. And therefore, by the end of this
video, you'll understand everything we've learned in the last 13 years. And therefore, if you want to
become a successful trader in 2026, it's important that you watch this entire video and take notes.
This way, you'll actually retain the information that we're going to teach you in this video. So
the goal by the end of this video is very simple. And that is we will try to help you master the
exact simple step by step plan to become a better trader this year. Even if you've never opened a
chart before or are just starting training as a beginner trader, I will show you what I do when I
do it. And most importantly, how I do it. And all of this will be step by step and simplified for you.
So in this video, first, we're going to talk about how to start trading. We're going to be going
through the brokers, the chart setups, then I'll show you one proven and simple system that we trade
every single day. And we have been trading this consistently since we have been profitable traders.
And then we'll go over a full technical analysis guide. And this is going to be a very important
part in this video, if you want to see consistency, finally, we'll end off with psychology and tips
and how to become a better trader this year. So if you're excited for this, make sure to leave
this video a like, let's see if we can get 5000 likes on this video. But with this being said,
who does this system truly work for? Because there's some trading systems that may not work for
everyone. Well, the beauty of our trading system is this works for anyone that has a full time job.
If you're working in nine to five, if you're a full time student, if you're working part time,
or if you're busy parents and you don't have enough time to sit in front of the markets all day,
the system that we have created allows us to trade for about 90 minutes a day. Therefore,
if you are busy and you have other commitments outside of trading with friends, family, school,
or work, we're able to trade for the first 90 minutes of the day. And then we can do the important
things with our time that truly matter. So here's the truth. To become a successful trader,
you need to put in the work. This is a requirement. And I know this sounds obvious,
but you'd be shocked on how many traders truly get stuck not doing the work. And that's why when
you hear only 10% of traders become successful, it's because 90% simply didn't put in the work
required to become profitable. And this is why today you'll walk away with the exact blueprint
on how to become a real trader that uses one setup, one system and repeats it daily. Because
remember, money follows the process. If you are a process focused trader, the profits will follow
the process. However, it is not the other way around. When you're a new trader and you're trying to make
money, trading will only get harder for you. Therefore, in this video, we'll show you the process that
allows the profits to follow the process. So with this being said, let's get into how to start trading.
I'm now going to hand it over to Jada. We'll explain the simple tools you need to actually
start your trading career the right way. And this will be a simplified guide on all the tools you
need to start your trading career. All right, Tony, thanks for handing it off. I do want to mention
everything that we talk about in today's video will be linked in the description below. So if
you do want to use the softwares and tools that we use going into 2026, you guys can click the link
in the description below. We do have the best deals on everything. So make sure to take advantage
of that. And with that being said, now I'm going to get into exactly how to start trading, starting
off with the broker and charting setup. We'll also be talking about the tools that we use every single
day to trade in the markets. And when you first start trading, most of you think that you need a
complex software, you need 1000 monitors on your screen, you need a crazy PC setup. In reality,
you don't need a Wall Street setup to start trading in the markets. So all we need is a broker
slash charting software. We're going to be marking up all our charts on trading view. And then we're
going to be looking to execute our trades on MooMoo. As you can see right here, we're currently on
trading view. This is where we're going to be marking up all our charts. And then for our
executions and where we're going to place our trades is going to be on something called MooMoo.
This is a great broker if you trade stocks, futures and options. So let's head back onto trading
view. And the first thing that we're going to do is go up into this product section. And we're
going to click on the super charts. And as you can see right here, we have now a chart pulled up of the
S&P 500. So the S&P 500 is an index ETF that tracks 500 of the biggest companies on the New York
Stock Exchange. And I'm just going to give a basic overview of trading view and how we can use
trading view. So first things first, as you can see, this is what we have on the chart. We have our
timeframes in the top left and we can choose all the different timeframes that we want to be looking
for when it comes to trading. On the right hand side here, what we have is our watch list. I already
have a watch list set up, but you can see I've sectioned it off into futures. I have it sectioned
off into indices where I have the spy cues by IWM. And then I have tech names, which are names that
we trade on a daily basis like Tesla, Nvidia, AMD, Apple. These are tech names within the make seven.
Now let's go on to some tools that we'll be looking for when it comes to trading. As you can see,
we have a bunch of different tools. We have trend lines, we can draw boxes. There's drawing
tools as well. So there's so many different ways you can use trading view, which is a great platform
to use, especially if you're a beginner trader looking to get into the markets. We have plenty of
videos on exactly how to use trading view as a beginner day trader. I'll make sure to leave a link
in the description at the very end of the video. But right here, this is where the foundation is built
right here on trading view by looking at the charts, by looking at the candles. Now let's understand the
basics of candlestick formations and how we can use it in our trading. So as you can see right here,
what we have on the charts is a bunch of candlesticks. So when you first start trading,
you can go into this candlestick section. You can go into the top left and there's a bunch of
different variations that you can look at a chart. You can look at a line chart. You can look at a
bar chart. You can look at a candlestick chart. The candlestick chart is going to be our preferred
preference on how we trade. And primarily, the overall thesis of how we trade is we're going to be
looking for trends in the markets. We're going to be looking for higher highs, higher lows, and we're
going to be looking for clear trends to capture to trade towards the upside. But as you can see,
there's so many different candlesticks on a chart. Number one, we have to understand what candlesticks
are. And if you look onto the charts, you'll see thousands of different candlesticks. And really,
it's broken down into two different candlesticks, which are up close candles and down close candles.
And all candles have what's called a open low high close. And for a bearish candle, it's an open high
low close, basically how every single candlestick forms on the right hand side, we have our open price
pushes lower, and then we end up creating a low in the markets. And you can see price ends up pushing
back higher where the buyers step in, we create a high for the candle, and then we end up having our
close. And this is what makes up a bullish candle. And on the left hand side, we have a bearish candle.
So we have our open, we create a high price ends up pushing lower, we create a low, and then we have
our close, which is called our bearish candle. And right here, as you can see, we have our bodies,
and then we have our wicks, which are our shadows. And this is really the basics of candlesticks. So
we'll go a little bit more in depth in a bit on exactly how candlesticks form, where should they
form the different types of shapes, the different locations on where to look for certain candlesticks
and when. But basically, this is the foundation of what you see on the charts every day. If you
go back onto the charts now, we're currently on the daily timeframe. Now you'll be able to see
that there are down close candles, which in this case, I have marked out as black. We have up close
candles or green candles, which in this case, for me is great. If you go onto different types of
timeframes, so we can go onto the one hour chart, look at how many more candles that we have marked
out, we can go onto the five minute timeframe, and you can see a bunch of candles marked out here
on a chart. If you go onto the one minute timeframe, you can see how many candlesticks are on the charts
here. And now we're on the one minute timeframe. And what this represents is one single minute. So
every single candle represents 60 seconds or one minute worth of price action. So depending on the
timeframe that we're on, there's going to be different types of information. And our job as
traders is being able to identify key levels in the charts to look for profitable day trades in the
markets. So we want to position ourselves in good areas where we can have low risk and high reward,
where we can trade within the trend and capture price movements to make money. So with this being
said, now I'm going to hand it back off to Tony and he's going to be going over our bread and
butter system and the setups that we look for on a day to day basis. Alright, so the main bread and
butter system that we trade is called the break and retest strategy. Now this is a very simple
system to actually execute, but you need to understand how it truly works. So let's talk about how we
can use the break and retest. And remember, I'm going to simplify this with examples. So if you're
a little bit confused right now, don't worry, this will make much more sense. So essentially,
if we look over to the left hand side of the screen here, we can see that there is a clear key level
here. And every time price came up into this area or these candlesticks, you can see they got rejected
once, twice, three times, and then finally broke out. What does this mean? This means that this key
level is called resistance. So we're just going to put our for resistance. What this means is every
time we were at this level, there were sellers sitting here and the sellers were overpowering buyers. So
S is for sellers and B is for buyers. At this key level, sellers were overpowering buyers and kept
wanting the stock to move back to the downside. However, we finally got the breakout or the break
when we finally broke above this resistance over here for a move to the upside. This means the
selling liquidity that was sitting here prior with all these levels over here, that has now been
mitigated and buyers are now in control of the market as we pushed above resistance. Every single
uptrend, as we can see here, this is an uptrend because we have a low right here, a higher low
and a higher low, which simply shows that the stock is moving to the upside. However,
what you need to understand is every single uptrend needs a pullback. So for the break and
retest to work, remember the resistance we had here? Well, now that resistance is actually turned
into support because we know that sellers were overpowering buyers over here. So buyers know when
we come back into this level, buyers now need to overpower sellers. And you can see when we come
back into this area, we have a little bit of indecision here. However, once we start getting these
bullish green candles showing that buyers do want to move this trade back to the upside,
this is where we would look to enter this break and retest trade for a move to the upside. And that
is how the break and retest works in the most simple way. And remember, everything that I'm going
to teach you in this video revolves around this one system and this one strategy. To start making
consistent results in the market, you need to choose one setup that you can align with. One setup
can make you a consistent trader if you can learn it and master it. In this video, I'm going to
teach you the five primary setups that I trade on a consistent basis. Out of all of these setups,
you can choose which one you align with most. And remember, in the link in the description, I have a
free playlist that goes over every single one of these setups in much more detail that you can watch
after this video. But let's get into the setups. The first strategy we're going to be talking
about is the first candle strategy. In this strategy, one candle can tell us everything we need to know
because the problem is that as a new trader, a lot of traders focus on the full range of the stock.
In this example here, we can see we have a lot of information. There's a lot of candles. There's
some sellers in the market. There's some buyers in the market. But what does this mean? When you're
looking at candlesticks and there's nothing else on the chart, this can be confusing, especially if
you're a new trader. So to make this absolutely simple, rather than focusing on all of that noise,
what we're going to do is focus on the first candle of a new market session. What this means
is I personally trade the New York session. So the New York session is what we're going to focus
on in this video for this setup. And remember, all the strategies and setups that I'm going to
explain in this video work on stocks, options for crypto and forex, and all of them are going to be
used at the same time, which is going to be the New York session, no matter what instrument you're
trading. Now, the New York session opens up at 930 AM Eastern. This is the time that you need to
understand is going to be the most volatile and the time that we need to focus in on for the first
candle strategy. All we're going to do is use three steps for step one. We're going to mark out the
high and we're going to mark out the low of the first five minute candle of the New York open.
Once we do this, and remember, this candle is the 930 AM candle and it will be on the five minute
time frame. So we're going to mark out the high and low. The next thing we have to do for step two
is simply wait for a candle to close above the five minute range for a candle to close above.
As we can see, this is the body here. So this shaded area is the body. The little lines up here and
down here, these are called wicks. We need to wait for the body to close above the five minute high.
So once we get a body to close above the five minute high, this shows us in a very simple way
that the stock is trending to the upside. Therefore, the likelihood of us taking a trade for a
long side move or a by position and making that trade win is much more likely. Once we get that
five minute candle closure above, we then want to go to the one minute time frame for step three
and look for a retest and continuation. In this trade here, remember, I trade the break and
retest. Now you can see it a little bit more clearly. We had resistance here resistance here.
Once the resistance on the five minute high broke out, we then had a retest right here on this candle
on this candle is where we would enter in on for this move back to the upside. This is extremely
simple. And for our entries and stops, like I said, we're going to be entering in on this candle
right over here when we come back for the retest with strong price action. And remember, we're
going to talk much more in depth on price action and exactly how to read it a little bit later in this
video. So make sure to stay tuned for that. Our stop loss can simply be the stop of the candle
or this impulsive candle that broke above on the one minute timeframe of this five minute high.
And our profit targets need to be a two R multiple. Every trade that I take has a two hour
multiple. And all it to our multiple means is if my risk level over here is $100, I'm risking $100.
If we break below this candle over here, that means my profit target needs to be at least $200
every time. That means I make $200 for every $100 of risk that I'm putting on my trades.
So once again, to recap for step number one, we're going to mark out the five minute high.
And we're going to mark out the five minute low. After this, we're going to go to step two where we
need to wait for the five minute high candle closure above this level. As we can see, this first time
we would have got faked out because the five minute high did not close above. Remember, it's the body
that needs to close above. And this one we just had a wick. However, in this example, we actually
got the body to close above. So now it has validated that we're above the five minute high.
Now we can go to the one minute timeframe. And on the one minute timeframe, we're simply going to look
for the retest. As we can see here, this is the retest that we got. We can put our stop loss at the
break of structure. And remember, we're going to talk about market structure and technical analysis
much more in depth in this video. And then we can simply target out a two R multiple
or continuation in this trade. And though I'm showing you an example of this trade,
this is the exact same trade that I took live in front of thousands of traders. And you can see
the exact results that this trade had in the exact executions that I had for this trade
using the simple five minute opening range strategy. And this is truly how simple the first setup is.
Now after this, the next strategy is a previous day high and the previous day low strategy.
This one also only requires one candle. However, this one is a little bit different than the last one.
This is because instead of marking out the first five minutes, we're going to mark out the previous
day high and we're going to mark out the previous day low. So we simply focus in only when the stock is
near the high or when the stock is near the low. Why should we focus on the previous day high and low?
This is because we know we only trade the New York Stock Exchange open. This happens from 9.30 AM to 4
PM Eastern. And this is when the most volume in the market occurs. Therefore, if we focus in on the
previous day high and the previous day low, these areas of supply and demand are where the most
sellers and where the most buyers are sitting. And therefore similar to the five minute,
this just gives us a little bit more context in terms of resistance turning into support or support
turning into resistance. All we want to do is go on the daily time frame and we're going to mark
out the previous day high and the previous day low. Now this is going to be one candle where we
mark out the high and low on the daily time frame. We can also go over to the 15 minute time frame
and really adjust our levels to really make sure we have the correct previous day high and the previous
day lows. And from there, all we're looking for is very similar to the other example. And that is going
to be continuation. If the stock breaks above the previous day high, we're looking for the retest for
continuation. If the stock breaks below the previous day low, we're looking for the retest for continuation
to the downside. Once again, we mark out day one over here. Remember, this is the previous day or
yesterday. And then the day opens up at nine 30 AM in the morning the next day. And that's when
we would trade these levels. So the way we would trade this is step one, we mark out the previous day
high and the previous day low. Once again, this is a very simple step. We simply look to mark out from
nine 30 AM to four PM. And this is going to be the eastern standard timing. And we can do this on the
daily time frame. We can also adjust our levels like I said on the five minute or the 15 minutes time
frame. Once we do this for step two, we wait for the stock to break above or below the previous day
higher, the previous day low. In this example, we can see the previous day high. And this is the
stock breaking above. Remember, we're on the five minute timeframe because we want that confirmation
entry. Once we get a break above the previous day high, this is where we're now going to be
looking for the retest on the one minute timeframe. So one thing I want you to notice,
we are looking for the breakout on most of these setups on the five minute, but we are executing on
the one minute timeframe. So as we can see here, now we're simply going to wait for that break and
retest. Once we got the break above, now the next step is to wait for the retest back into this level
for potential continuation back to the upside. And here we can see once we got the retest on the
one minute timeframe, we waited for a little bit stronger price action. That's exactly what this
candle gave us right here. We put our stop loss at the break of the candle that broke above. And
once again, this is on the one minute timeframe, and we're looking for at least a two R multiple.
In this example, this trade was actually around a seven R multiple. This means for every $100
that we were risking, we were actually making $700 of potential profit. And finally, the last
setup that I want to talk about in this video is the pre market high and low retest. This one
works is what if we open up in between the previous day high and the previous day low? So we just
talked about the previous day high and the previous day low retest. But what if the stock doesn't open
above this level? What if the stock doesn't lows below this level? How can we trade days that are
in between the range of the previous day high and the previous day low? Of course, we can use
the first candle strategy, which was the first setup, but another setup that we can use in combination
is the pre market high and the pre market low strategy as well. The New York Stock Exchange open
is from nine 30 AM to four PM Eastern. However, we then have pre market pre market occurs from
four AM Eastern to nine 30 AM Eastern. So it is the exact opposite timing of this. And this is
what we can potentially use as well for a move to the upside or to the downside. And this would be
early in the day if we are opening in between the range of the previous day high and the previous day
low for this setup. All we're going to do is mark out the pre market high. And we're going to mark
out the pre market low, this is from four AM to nine 30 AM Eastern. We mark out the high and we mark
out the low, then similar to the other examples, we then simply wait for the pre market high or the
pre market low to be broken. In this example, the pre market high is being broken here. This is
once again on the five minute timeframe that we're waiting for this breakout. And then we're simply
looking to enter in on the retest on the one minute timeframe. In this example, you can see this is the
pre market high level here. We got the clear breakout on the five minute on the one minute we came back
for the retest. We look for that strong price action. Once we get it over here, we then enter into the
trade looking for at least a two R multiple with our stop loss at a break of structure and our
profit targets. Once again, out of two R multiple. So just to make this one extremely clear, we mark
out pre market high and we mark out pre market low. That's step one step two is to wait for a candle
closure above this level. You can see the body of this candle closed above the pre market high.
Notice how there is no body closure here. This would be fake illiquidity. Therefore, we're waiting
for the five minute body to close on all of these setups. Once we get that five minute candle closure,
that's when we go over to the one minute timeframe. We look for the retest and continuation. And you
can see this trade right here, a clear stop, clear profit targets at least a two R multiple. And
this was a solid trade using the pre market high and the pre market low. Now it's important to mention,
I just showed you three of the setups that are very simple to actually trade in real time.
And remember, all of these setups are similar, but there's a little bit of a twist to give you an edge
in every single market. Now, if you do want more information on any of these setups or more advanced
setups as well, make sure to click the playlist in the description where I have multiple videos
on the other setups as well. So, so far we've covered how to start your trading career. We went over a
quick introduction to technicals. We went over one proven system on how to trade it. But now this
is going to be one of the most important parts in this video. And this will be how to master
technical analysis and everything you truly need to read the markets like a professional trader.
So, let's get into it. So, Tony just went over our bread and butter system. Now I'm going to be
going over how to master technical analysis and everything that we should be looking for when it
comes to trading the break and retest. But first, we have to understand what is the biggest cause of
trading failure. So, as you know, the statistic out there online is quite alarming. About 90% of
traders fail when it comes to trading in the markets. And there's a one main core reasoning on
why this is the case. The biggest reason why majority of traders fail is because they have a lack of
profitable and repeatable system. They come into the markets with a gambling mindset. They really
don't have a repeatable system and they don't understand what they're looking for on a day to day basis.
They're really coming into the markets blindly. They hope that price goes in their favor and then
they can make money. But at the end of the day, hope is not a strategy. And unless you have a proven
edge and repeatable system, you're not going to become a profitable trader. But guess what?
We just went over our bread and butter trading system, which is the break and retest. And we also
went over all the setups that we use on a day to day basis. The first candle rule, the previous
that high and low breaking retest, the pre market high and low breaking retest. So one candle rule,
we went over all our setups and our full strategy. But here's the truth. Having a profitable strategy
isn't enough. We just laid out the foundation with our strategy and system along with the setups.
Is that all it takes in order to become a successful trader? If it was that easy, then a lot more people
would become profitable. But just because you have a profitable and repeatable system, what do you
lack as traders? Most of you guys lack confidence and conviction in yourself and in the strategy and
system. Some of you guys lack experience from holding losers and cutting winners. These are
some very common mistakes when it comes to trading is that you don't have the experience and the
execution in order to actually trade in the markets. And some common misbeliefs and mistakes that most
traders have when they first start trading is that they think the market makers are against me. As you
can see, you enter into a nice break and retest, you have your stop just a break below. You end up
getting stopped out, but then price ends up hitting your profit target. And one of the more common
mistakes that a lot of beginners traders say is that the market makers are against me and that
trading is unfair. Well, that is not the case. You just had a poorly planned trade. If you actually
had the correct stop, which is at the breaker structure, you would actually been able to hold this trade
because you had a proper stop loss, which would have been a break underneath this key pivot point.
And you would have been able to ride this trade towards your targets. Another common excuse is
that you'll say I'll wait for more confirmation. So now you understand the setup, you can see it in
real time. You have a nice break with displacement, we're coming back to retest,
you mentioned you're going to wait for more confirmation and guess what happens. You did not
trust yourself because you have a lack of experience and confidence in your trading abilities. And you
can see price ended up having a perfect retest right off our key levels. And we end up having that super
solid push back up and towards our higher timeframe targets. And now you're kicking yourself because
you're like, damn, I realized the setup, I knew what was going to happen. But I just couldn't find
myself to execute the trade. Another one is let me enter into this a plus trade here with a clear
plan. So you have a higher timeframe setup, we're coming into our retest level, we have buyer stepping
in, we're going to have a stop loss just to break below. And we're going to let this trade play out.
But as you can see, I ended up hitting our stop loss and it's reversing, but I'll just hold.
And what happens is that you just blew your account because you didn't fall your original plan. So
we had a solid plan. Unfortunately, this trade didn't work out. Not all trades are going to work
out when it comes to trading. Not everything is going to be 100% win rate. And in this case,
you didn't follow your plan. And because you didn't follow your plan, you blew your account and you paid
the price. And every trader has made these mistakes, you are not alone. Every profitable trader has
been through exactly what you're going through, maybe in this exact moment. So just understand that
in order to become profitable, you have to make these mistakes and learn from these mistakes.
And that brings me to my triple E's formula. So we talked about the education, which is really
having a strategy and system. Once you have the education, you need to be able to execute along
with having experience in the markets. And this is where that triple E formula comes in,
is that you need to have all three of these in order to become profitable. You can't just have
the education without the execution and experience. This is where most of you guys are most likely at
right now. You understand the charts, you have the system, you have the foundation. But what you lack
in is execution along with experience. And what does that mean? That means you need to have real-time
market experience in order to see these setups in real time. And you have to combine all three together
in order to become profitable. So now let's play a game to test our knowledge to see what we've
learned so far in this video. So would you take this trade? As you can see right here, we have
our pre-market lows, we have our five-minute range low. And as you can see, price pushes higher,
ultimately breaks underneath our five-minute range low. And now we're retesting our key levels.
We have weak price action, plus we have a confirmation candle as well. Right now we're on the one-minute
time frame. So just strictly looking at this chart currently without any higher time frame context
or any other confluences as well, would this be a trade you would take? Most of you guys would
be looking at this trade. You would look to enter here. You would mention this is a textbook setup,
right? Eight plus, right? Strong candle close. And you can't lose on this trade based off of the
break and retest. But guess what happens? As you can see right here, price ends up having that nice
confirmation candle. We end up pushing lower, but ultimately we end up having a super-sharp reversal
and we ended up getting stopped out. And now you question, how did I lose on this trade?
What did I do wrong? This strategy doesn't work. Let me switch trading strategies. And these are
all things that I said when I first started trading. As soon as my trades stop working,
I started questioning myself and I started questioning the strategy if it was actually profitable or not.
And what you have to understand is that you could have the perfect break and retest and it still
fails. Think about that. When it comes to trading, you can have everything aligned together,
but ultimately that trade setup still fails. What is the reasoning behind that? Well, number one,
trading is all about probabilities and risk management. There's nothing certain in trading.
The only thing certain is that there's going to be uncertainty. So that's why trading is all about
probabilities. But with that being said, how can you be in a top 10% of traders making money? Well,
guess what? Context and logic is everything when it comes to trading. If you don't have context and
logic, it is going to be very hard for you to have conviction and confidence. So understanding this
is going to be very key, especially when you're trading the break and retest. And one of my favorite
things to do to give us that confidence and conviction is by simply trading with the trend and also being
aligned with the higher timeframes. So what does this mean? As you can see right here, we have multiple
timeframes. We have the one minute, we have the five minute, we have the 15 minute, we have the one
hour daily weekly. There's so many timeframes when it comes to trading, and you might be a little bit
confused, especially if you're a beginner trader, because you're very confused on all the candles on
the charts, all the different timeframes. What are we supposed to use? Since we do have a lot of
timeframes and sometimes it can be overcomplicated, it can be fairly broad. But what you have to understand
is that every single timeframe plays a role in the markets. And what I want to break down quickly
is my four step foundation on exactly how to increase your win rate to really be able to identify
those A plus setups when it comes to trading, where that's where our bread and butter comes in. So
we're going to talk about our bias, our narrative, the entry slash setup, which we already covered,
and then we're going to go over risk management as well. So number one bias, what does bias mean?
It's really understanding the direction of the market. And it's simply asking ourselves,
are we going higher or are we going lower, higher meaning bullish, lower meaning bearish.
So when we're bullish, what we need is an upward trend. Basically, when price moves higher over time,
forming higher highs and higher lows, as you can see right here, price is moving higher,
and we're forming higher lows, and we're pushing towards upside. And in downward trend,
it's the exact opposite when price moves lower over time, forming lower highs and lower lows.
As you can see, price is moving lower. We're creating a trend towards the downside. And as you
can see, price is ultimately moving lower. And then we have sideways price action. When price moves
in a flat or sideways range without a clear higher highs or higher lows. And this is what's called
consolidation or range. As you can see, price is just ranging in between these key levels. This is
when we want to be hands off, because there's no clear trend in the markets. And this is what
it looks like here on a lawn chart. And this is quickly to explain it once more. As you can see,
we have our higher lows, we have our higher highs, followed by our higher lows, and our higher highs.
And you can see clear upwards trend in the market. We have the middle, which is a consolidation where
there's no clear trend, where price is ranging. And then on the right hand side, we have our lower
highs, followed by our lower lows, lower highs. And you can see we're in a clear down trend in
the markets where prices pushing lower. So with this being said, now we understand the trends.
What's next? So now we understand the trends in the markets. What's next? What's next is understanding
how strong or how weak of a bias that we can have. So as you can see right here, when we have a
strong bias, or what I consider high probability trades is when timeframes are aligned. So when the
monthly, weekly, daily, the four hour charts are all aligned, that's when we have a strong bias,
or whatever timeframe that you decide to be your higher timeframes. When everything is aligning
together, that usually means we're in a very strong trend in the markets. When do we have a
weak bias or low probability environments, when the timeframes aren't aligned? As you can see,
the monthly is bullish, but the weekly is bearish, the daily is bullish, but the four hours bearish.
When timeframes aren't aligned, that's called timeframe misalignment. That's usually when we're
in more ranging markets, or the markets aren't as clear on the higher timeframes. We have to be a
lot more cautious because we're not as clear on what's happening on the higher timeframes,
and there's no trends in the markets. So as you can see right here, we're on the NQ slash QQQ,
and we're on the daily timeframe. You can see we're clearly in an uptrend in the markets. We're
creating higher lows, higher highs, higher lows, and we have bullish structure, and we're continuing
to push higher. Next, what we want to understand is the narrative. If we're going to go higher,
where are we going to go higher from? If we're going to go lower, where are we going to go
lower from? Just because we're bullish doesn't mean we can just blindly buy. We need areas of interest
on where we want to frame a trade. And the same thing to the downside. If we're looking to go short,
where are we going to go short from? We just can't blindly sell. So what we're going to be looking
for is higher timeframe points of interest. And what does this mean? It really just means old highs
and old lows. As you can see based off of the break and retest on the daily chart, we have nice
resistance multiple touches that turn into support. You can see price pushes higher. And then once again,
resistance turning into support and so forth. And we end up having this nice continuation high.
Where we want to be taking trades is around these break and retest levels, because these are going
to be where the best opportunities occur. Next, let's talk about our entry slash setup
timeframe. And this is really done on the lower time frames on the one five and 15 minute. As you
can see right here, if we have a higher timeframe narrative, which is on the daily chart, and we look
for an entry point all the way down onto the one minute timeframe, what is the issue in this case?
The issue is that there's too much distance between the time frames. If you go from the daily
chart down into the one minute timeframe, you have to go from the daily to the four hour to the one
hour to the five to the one minute, there's too much distance. And by the time you get down
into that one minute timeframe, it's going to be very hard to understand what we're looking for and
can get confused. And right here is a cheat sheet that I've created. You guys can take a screenshot
of this, but it's basically understanding where your narrative is in comparison to your entry
timeframe. So for example, if we have a weekly and daily narrative, this just means we're looking
to form our trades on the weekly and daily chart, where should our entry be? It should be on the daily
and four hour, we should really only be two time frames away. And right here, this is primarily
for position trading and long term investing for the four hour and one hour, we can be on the one
hour and 15 minute for entry. And this is really good for swing trading. And then for day trading,
we want to have a narrative on the 15 minute. And you guys, you can see we're only two time frames
away. We have the five minute, and then we have the one minute for entry. And this is really good
for our day trades. This is primarily what we'll use as day traders is we'll have a narrative on the
15 and we'll use entries on the one minute timeframe. And then finally, for our risk management approach,
the timeframe we used is dependent on the narrative and entry timeframe. So for example,
if we have our narrative on the 15 minute and our entry on the one minute, where can we manage
our risk, we can manage our risk on the five or the one minute timeframe. The time frames that we can
use is a timeframe between the narrative and entry time frames to manage risk. So if you want to have
a tight risk manager and approach, we can do this on the one minute timeframe. If we want to give
it a little bit more wiggle room, then we can use this on the five minute timeframe. So this is going
to be key. So this is going to be key when it comes to the markets. Now with this being said,
let's go on to some examples that I have for us today. So first example that we have here is
Palantir. As you can see on the higher time frames, I have our points of interest marked out here.
We have our key levels of resistance, we have our key levels of support. If you want to be looking
for continuation higher, since so far we are building up higher lows, we can be looking for
the break above our key resistance and look for this level to turn into support for continuation
higher. As you can see right off the bat, breaking above a key level with a strong candle close. So
what we have here is our pre market highs along with a key level within the first five minutes of
market open. You can see really strong buyers stepping in right off the bat. So with this being said,
higher timeframe that we have is bullish. And now the lower time frames, we have our bullish as well.
So now we can be looking for continuation higher. So now what we're going to be doing is waiting
for a retest entry for continuation. So Tony talked about earlier, the pre market high and
key level slash retest, we have an impulsive move towards upside with displacement. As you can
see, now we really just want to see a retest of the level for a push back towards the upside.
As you can see price comes back retest plus strong price action, come right back down
in towards our pre market high and slash key level. You can see price shows that buyers are stepping
in by these lower wicks multiple lower wicks. And what we have here is what's called our confirmation
candle. So once we have this confirmation candle, which closes above its previous candle,
this is a good signature in price that we're going to continue higher. And what is our confirmation
entry? So as you can see, there's two different type of entry models that we'll use when it comes
to trading the markets, we have our conservative entry, which just means buyers are stepping in.
This can be signaled by hammer stick handles by lower wicks, indicating that buyers are present
in the markets. So this is our conservative entry. And then we have our most conservative entry,
which is my personal favorite. We have the buyers stepping in plus the confirmation candle.
So it's the exact same thing, but you're waiting for one more candle, which really means this
confirmation candle right once this candle closes above its previous candle high. This is a good
signature and price to confirm price higher. So with that being said, we have two different entry
models that we can use, we can use a conservative or the most conservative entry model. And these
are the two best entry models to use when it comes to trading the break and retest. As you can see,
now this is what the end result looks like. We have our entry on this candle close. Our stop loss can
be a break underneath our candle low here on that confirmation. And then we can be looking for targets
to push back up and towards high of date and above. You can see right here, this is what the
one minute timeframe looks like. And this is what the five minute timeframe looks like. You can see
buyers stepped in very nicely, a nice continuation back higher. And this is exactly how to use all four
steps in combination with one another. And as you can see, these are the executions right here.
And these are also the broker executions as well. Now, let's go on to the next example that I have
for us today, which is on Tesla. And the next example that we have here is Tesla on the higher
timeframes. And as you can see right here, our bias is fairly bullish. As you can see, we're making
higher highs, higher lows, higher highs, and we're continuing to push higher. Currently, as you can
see, we have a key level of resistance, we're creating what's called a flat top break. Now,
what we like to see is the break above hold above for this continued push towards the upside.
As you can see right here, price is now breaking above the key level with strong candle close.
As you can see, what we have here is your previous day highs in our pre-market highs
within the first five minutes of market open. We have a really nice push towards the upside,
indicating bullish price action, higher timeframes bullish, lower timeframe is bullish here as well.
Now we have two potential trading opportunities. What we have is our five minute range high,
along with our previous day highs, we can either be looking for the five minute range break,
or now the retest off our previous day highs for this continued push towards the upside.
And as you can see right here, price ends up having a nice push above our five minute range
high. So what we're going to do now is wait for the five minute range high retests,
along with our order block for continuation towards the upside. As you can see right here,
now we're waiting for that retest with a strong candle close, price comes back down into that
order block along with our five minute range high, nice strong candle close here as well,
entries right off our key level with a stop just a break below. And now for our targets,
we can be looking for high day plus a continued push back towards the upside. And as you can see,
this is what the one minute timeframe looks like. And on the left hand side,
this is what the five minute timeframe looks like. So this was a nice, solid,
higher timeframe setup here as well. And this brings me back to my main point in terms of thinking
with context and logic is when you stop becoming a pattern trader, that's when you start becoming
a real trader. If all the time, you're just thinking strictly just based off the pattern in itself,
right, our edge comes in when we're thinking with context and logic, how to avoid the unnecessary
trades based off of our context and logic based off the conferences, based off our entry confirmations,
that's when you'll start seeing real success in the markets, when you start thinking in terms of
context and logic. So with that being said, now I'm going to hand it back off to Tony,
and he's going to take it from me. Okay, so by this point of the video,
there's some hard truths that I need to tell you about trading that most other traders on YouTube
simply will not tell you trading is not a get rich quick business. You won't see success overnight
or just one lucky trade is not enough to become a consistent trader over years and years. It takes
making mistakes to become a profitable trader. And most importantly, it takes countless hours of
learning to see true consistency in the market. So far, in this video, you discovered something
powerful. And this was the full skill of real trading laid out to you step by step throughout
this video. So now you've got the roadmap, the checklist, and the proof that this system truly
works. However, if you want more help and want to learn live with me and jade up every day, this is
where we are proud to present to you traders lab in traders lab, we live trade every single day.
Therefore, you can see every single trade that I've taken in the last two years, and every day I
will be live trading in front of you as well. You will also receive full recordings to the 14 day
bootcamp we have done, you will get a one on one implementation call when you join, meaning that a
head coach will come on and make sure that we can assess your current trading performance and see
where you lie so we can give you curated steps in your trading career. And we have weekly coaching
calls with myself and jade up every single week going through new lessons and implementation on how
to actually see consistency in trading. We have thousands of hours of live trading recordings from
the last two years every single trade I've taken has been recorded live along with lessons that I
have done every single week breaking down concept strategies and systems. And finally, you will get
full discord access and the entire accelerator course to help you learn even more on how to trade. If
you are interested in this, make sure to click the first link in the description, make sure to sign
up for the waitlist. And as a bonus, we will also be giving free never seen before content and education
on trading in your email. So make sure when you sign up to keep an eye out for that. If this video
helped you make sure to leave a like if you have any questions, put them in the comments down below,
make sure to subscribe to the channel and I will see you next week with a brand new video.